# Joshuah Gutierrez

# Email - LinkedIn - Portfolio - Github

My strong critical thinking skills propelled my career in Hospitality Management, which tragically ended in my struggle with sobriety. I found my motivation and inner peace while studying MERN-stack development, resulting in my roles as a Web Developer, Instructor, Mentor, and Manager. My life experience will allow me to empathize with and drive your Frontend Engineering team.

#### Skills and tools

Front-end: HTML, CSS, Javascript, Jquery, Python, Node, React, Redux Sass, Typescript Back-end: Node-express, MongoDB, Mongoose, Python, Django, Postgres C, GO Methodologies: Object Oriented Programming, MVC Pattern, REST-ful API, Big O

Deployment: Git, GitHub, Command Line, Heroku, Firebase

## **Work Experience**

# Alphaworks / Lead React Apprentice from 2022 - 2023

Direct supervisor of 11

- Utilize my React expertise to provide students with valuable knowledge through a meticulously crafted curriculum I personally designed, equipping them with essential real-world skills.
- Transitioned from my initial roles as an Instructor and Project Manager to a dedicated Mentor with a strong emphasis on enhancing individuals' soft skills. -Effectively Thriving in an agile environment, expertly managing diverse teams and 8 ambitious projects simultaneously.
- Ensure a safe environment for all and maintain payroll to the best of my ability.
- Conducted regular biweekly one-on-one sessions to ensure that each apprentice remained up-todate with their educational progress while addressing any concerns or uncertainties they may have had.

#### Enki.Ai / Full Stack Developer from 2021 - 2021

Technologies Used: Javascript React Redux Sass

- I spearhead projects, taking complete ownership from design wireframes to full Proof of Concept.
- I facilitate coordination, orchestrate daily meetings, set weekly sprints, and directly report progress to the company's CTO.
- I harness Enki's API to create a dynamic search page that swiftly retrieves relevant information based on various search requests. It intelligently organizes and displays results by title.

## **Case Studies/Concept Projects**

# Pokemon trading card game clone - 03/2020

Web-based game / Solo Project

Technologies Used: HTML CSS Javascript Jquery

- The goal Clone the PTCG, allowing users to play against a computer opponent.
- Custom CSS showcases CSS art replica of a Pokeball. Game logic is written in Javascript, covering the complete life-cycle of a round/game in a card game.

#### Poke-tracker - 04/2020

Full-Stack Pokedex / Team Project

Technologies Used: HTML CSS EJS express Mongoose MongoDB, Pokemon API

- Cloned the Pokedex, enabling user tracking of captured Pokemon and providing game item information.
- Implemented a data structure with 2 relationships to track multiple trainers' collections in one

#### **Education**

# **Software Engineering Immersive**

General Assembly, San Francisco

Graduated, June 2020

# React, Redux bootcamp; Node.Js, MongoDB bootcamp; 2020 Javascript bootcamp; Udemy (Online)

On-Going

# **Python Programming**

Codecademy (Online) On-Going

#### **Software Engineering**

42 Silicon Valley, Fremont CA 2018 - 2019

# **Hobbies**

Video Games Snowboarding Wakeboarding Cooking Running

# Spoken languages

English Spanish account.

- Custom CSS and CSS art showcased design elements.
- Utilized a Pokemon API and MongoDB database to display and track users' captured Pokemon.
- Collaborated on a partner project, honing information management and effective communication skills between frontend and backend developers.

## Gayme-it - 05/2020

Reddit-clone / Solo-project

Technologies Used: Full-stack MERN app Mongo, Express, React, Node, CSS, Sass

- Goal was to create a Reddit clone focusing on Karma Voting
- Front end is build in React, Back end express api server, with MongoDB